Scatter!
散！
Morale is high and everyone is
ready to move into action
（シカク）皆の士気は極めて高く
いつ命令されても→
as soon as the order is given.
出撃できる状態にまで
仕上がっています。
Good.
（綱手）うむ。
All right. We can't just
stand around either!
（木ノ葉丸）よ～し　俺たちも
こうしちゃいられないんだなコレ。
（モエギ／ウドン）え？
（木ノ葉丸）モエギ　ウドン　行くぞコレ！
Moegi, Udon... Let's go!
（モエギ）はっ！
うわっ！
– Now, Udon!
– Right.
今よ　ウドン！
（ウドン）うん！
Fire Style! Burning Ash!
火遁　灰積焼！
（２人）うわ～！　ゴホッゴホッ…。
Hey, Konohamaru.
ちょっと　木ノ葉丸ちゃん。
やりすぎだよ　これ。
You're overdoing it.
Listen up. The village is
getting ready for war!
いいか？　今　里は
戦争の準備中なんだなコレ！
We have to be ready
俺たち　いつ招集が
かかってもいいように→
to answer the call to arms
at any time too!
用意しとかなきゃ
なんないんだな！
We're still genin,
僕たち　すぐに
戦場に行くことはないと思うよ。
so I doubt that we'll get
to battle right away.
Besides, aren't there still things
that kids like us have to do?
それに　私たちには
私たちなりに→
やらなきゃいけないことが
あるんじゃない？
なに　ノンキなこと言ってんだ！
How can you be so relaxed?
We've made progress since then.
俺たちは　あれから成長してる。
We have to distinguish ourselves
手柄立てて　ナルト兄ちゃんみたいな
里の英雄になるんだなコレ！
and become the heroes
of this village!
ibitsu na merodll de dekita aisareru beki ikimono da
Made from a distorted melody,
I'm a creature that should be loved
seika wa agerarenakute mo kokoro ga utatte iru kara
Even if I can't better myself,
I'll continue to sing from my heart
dore dake tsuyoi ame koete aisareru beki ikimono ka?
What storms must I overcome
To be a creature who should be loved?
yakusoku ga mamorenakute mo kokoro wa utatte iru kedo
Even if you can't keep your promise
My heart will keep on singing, but...
dono doa nokku shite aketara ii?
Which door should I knock on and open?
aketara doko e mukattara ii?
Once I open it, where should I go?
hitori ja kaerenai kara
I can't go home by myself
dareka o matte ita dake
I was just waiting for someone
kimi ga ima ichiban aitai hito wa dare?
Who is the one you want to meet the most?
kokoro no naka de dake hanaseru hito no kazu wa fuete iku
The number of people that I can only speak to in my heart
keep increasing
dakara tsuyoku naritakatta tada
So I just wanted to be strong
bokura mada yomitarinai monogatari
Our story just hasn't been told enough
muriyari owarenai koto wakattete
We know it's not something we can just quit
dare mo mina jibun no mama
Because we all want to be ourselves
tsuyoku naritakatta kara
We wanted to be strong
Naruto's Favorite Student
とにかく　里のために→
Anyway, the time has come
手柄を立てなきゃ
ならない時が来たんだ。
for us to achieve
great things for our village.
でも　木ノ葉丸君
僕ら　どうやればいいの？
But Konohamaru,
how are we gonna do that?
そうよ　口で言うのは
簡単だけど…。
Yeah, it's easier said than done.
う～ん　どうすれば…。
How can we?
あ…。
そうだ！
木ノ葉新聞なんだなコレ！
That's it! The Leaf News!
え？
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
（木ノ葉丸）
あのさ　木ノ葉新聞だけど→
Say, I'm from Leaf News.
今度の戦争のこと
取材しているんだなコレ。
We're going to collect data
about the impending war.
僕たち　この間の騒動のときは
みんなの避難に協力したんだ。
During the last incident,
we helped everyone evacuate.
それ以外に　何か
私たちにできることってある？
Is there anything else
that we can do?
（サクラ）あるわよ。　腕出して。
There sure is.
Hold out your hands.
（３人）うっ！
There!
（サクラ）それ…　さっさと運んで。
Okay, carry those.
ご苦労さま　助かったわ。
Thanks a lot.
That was a big help.
サクラ姉ちゃん　ちょっと待って。
Sakura, please wait.
You didn't tell us what
we can do to help in the war.
俺たち　今度の戦争で
何ができるか→
まだ聞いていないんだなコレ。
私たち　里のために働きたいの。
We want to do something for
the sake of the village.
うん！
Yeah!
（サクラ）あなたたち
もう里に貢献してるわ。
You're already doing something
for the sake for the village.
（３人）えっ？
この箱にはね→
This box contains medicine
to be used by the ninja
前線で戦う忍たちのために
使われる　薬が入ってるんだから。
who will be fighting
on the front lines.
Not like that!
そうじゃないんだ！
え？
もっと　ナルト兄ちゃんみたいに→
We want to do something bigger
すっげえ手柄が
立てたいんだなコレ！
like the kind of stuff
Big Brother Naruto does, you know?
なに言ってるの！
戦争は遊びじゃない！
What are you saying?
War is not playtime.
たくさんの人が傷つき
死んでしまうかもしれないの！
Many people will get hurt
and they may die!
軽々しく
手柄だなんて言わないで！
Don't speak so lightly of
distinguishing yourselves!
（木ノ葉丸）この～！　俺たちのこと
下忍だと思って→
Man! Looking down on us
just because we're genin!
バカにしてるんだなコレ！
But what Big Sister Sakura
said is true.
でも　サクラ姉ちゃんの
言うとおりだと思うよ。
うん…。
私たち　やっぱりみんなを…。
I guess we should just...
Don't give up so easily!
こんなことで
あきらめられないんだなコレ！
（シカマル）どうした？
ずいぶん荒れてんじゃねえか。
What's the matter?
You look kind of upset.
フンッ。
（木ノ葉丸）シカマル兄ちゃん！
Big Brother Shikamaru!
What do we have to do to
get on the front lines
どうすれば　前線に出て
暁と戦えるんだ？
and fight the Akatsuki?
ペインだって倒したし　もう一人前の
木ノ葉の忍だぞコレ！
I brought down Pain.
I'm a full-fledged Leaf ninja now!
ふ～ん…　じゃ　その一人前の
木ノ葉の忍に質問だ。
Well then, I have a question
for you, full-fledged Leaf ninja.
あ　あぁ…。
お前が守るべき玉ってのは　何だ？
Define the King that
you feel you must protect?
ギョク？
"King"?
フッ　その意味が
わかんないようじゃ→
If you don't know the meaning
of what I'm asking,
木ノ葉の忍としちゃ
一人前とは認めらんねえぜ。
then I cannot acknowledge you
as a full-fledged Hidden Leaf ninja.
な～んて　偉そうに
言ってみたものの→
Here I go, talking big.
Actually, I learned the answer
just recently myself.
俺も最近
わかったばっかだけどな。
まっ　そんな背伸びする必要は
ないんじゃねえか？
Anyway, there's no need to
push yourself so hard.
また話　聞いてやるよ。
I'll hear you out again sometime.
ほらよ。
Here.
玉？
玉って何だコレ？
Ball?
What does "ball" mean?
You're so dumb!
バカ！
（木ノ葉丸）みんな
わけわかんないこと言って→
I wish everyone would stop
giving us the run around!
ごまかすんだな　コレ！
ようし　こうなったら！
どうするの？
All right then.
What are you going to do?
誰を取材するの？
Who are we going to
interview next?
取材するんじゃない。
We're not going to
interview anyone.
We're going to demand that
戦争に参加できるように
直談判だコレ！
we be allowed to
take part in the war!
（綱手）バカもん！
You fool!
Why?!
どうしてだコレ！？　俺は里のために
前線に出て戦いたいんだ！
I want to fight for our village
on the front lines!
お前の出番はない！
There is no place for you there!
俺だって
ペインの一人を倒したんだ！
I brought down Pain by myself!
前線に出て戦う実力は
あるはずだコレ！
I am fully qualified to fight
on the frontlines!
執務の邪魔だ！
You are interfering with my work!
出て行け！
Get out!
木ノ葉丸君！
大丈夫！？
Konohamaru!
Are you okay?!
チクショウ！
Damn it!
何だコレ！
Why?!
((縄樹　１２歳の誕生日おめでとう。
Nawaki, happy twelfth birthday!
（縄樹）姉ちゃん
これってもしかして。
Big Sister, is this?
そう　初代火影　我らが
おじいさまの火影の首飾り。
Yes. It's the First Hokage's,
our grandfather's, necklace!
(大好き　姉ちゃん))
I love you, Big Sister!
Damn it.
ったく　もう。
Oh, someone is coming.
あっ　誰か来るよ。
怒られちゃう。
We'll get yelled at!
グオッ。
This way.
（イズモ）こちらです。
（コテツ）火影様がお待ちかねです。
Lady Hokage is expecting you.
（テマリ）ああ。
あれは確か…。
Right.
Hey, that's...
Temari, the older sister to
砂隠れ里　風影の姉　テマリさんよ。
the Kazekage of
the Hidden Sand Village.
風影？
Kazekage?
いい手があるんだな。
I have a good idea.
どういうこと？
What're you thinking?
風影から火影様への密書です。
This is a secret letter from
the Kazekage to you.
うむ　ご苦労。　確かに受け取った。
Yes, thank you.
I confirm that I have
received it from you.
しかし
この忙しいときにわざわざ…。
What a long way for you to come
during such a hectic time, just to deliver this.
いえ　同盟国である
木ノ葉の現状を→
Not at all. I wanted to personally
assess the situation
この目で確かめて
おきたかったものですから。
in Hidden Leaf Village,
a member of the alliance.
久しぶりの木ノ葉だろ。
かつての面影はないが→
It's been a while, hasn't it?
The shadows of the past are gone,
but please stay and rest.
ゆっくり休んでいってくれ。
ありがとうございます。
Thank you, but I must hurry
back to the village.
しかし　急ぎ里へ戻らねば
なりませんので　これにて。
Please excuse me.
シカマル兄ちゃん。
Brother Shikamaru!
なんだ　お前ら。
玉の意味でもわかったのか？
What is it?
Did you figure out
the meaning of "King"?
– Konohamaru's in trouble!
– Konohamaru is... He's...
木ノ葉丸ちゃんが大変。
木ノ葉丸君が…。
What's wrong?
どうした？
SAND
砂隠れの里の上忍テマリ。
Hidden Sand Jonin Temari!
俺の挑戦を受けてほしいんだなコレ。
はぁ？
You will accept my challenge!
どけ　怪我をするぞ。
それはどっちかな？
Move or you'll get hurt.
I wonder which one of us
will get hurt.
俺の名は猿飛木ノ葉丸。
My name is Konohamaru Sarutobi.
Grandson of the Third Hokage,
三代目の孫で
ナルト兄ちゃんの愛弟子だ。
Big Brother Naruto's
favorite student!
ナルトの？
挑戦から逃げるってことは→
Naruto's?
Running away from
this challenge will mean
俺を怖がってるって
解釈するんだなコレ。
that you fear me!
なんだと　このチビ？
Say that again, you brat!
いくぞコレ！
Here I come!
Fire Style! Burning Ash!
火遁　灰積焼。
First Star.
一の星。
うわぁ～！
ペッ　ペッ…。
どうやったんだコレ？
How'd you do that?
坊主　威勢がいいのは口だけか？
Hey, kid!
You're just talk, aren't you?
この～　坊主じゃない！
木ノ葉丸だコレ！
I'm not a kid! I'm Konohamaru!
手裏剣　影分身の術。
Kunai knives!
Shadow Clone Jutsu!
二の星。
Second Star!
クッ。
ふ～ん　猿飛一族も
ろくな跡継ぎは残ってないようだ。
It seems the Sarutobi Clan doesn't
have a decent heir left.
う～ん　こうなったら！
I have no choice.
影分身の術。
Multi Shadow Clone Jutsu!
チッ。
いくぞコレ！
Here I go!
は～っ！
♪～
三の星。
Third Star!
ぬぅ…　うわぁ～！
そこまで！
That's enough!
私への挑戦なんて
１００年　早いんだよ。
You're a hundred years away
from challenging me.
うぅ…。
ナルトの愛弟子と聞いたが
期待した分　損をしたな。
You said you were
Naruto's favorite student.
What a disappointment.
まっ　ナルトみたいなやつに
ろくな弟子ができるわけないか。
Well, I shouldn't have
expected a guy like Naruto
to have a decent student.
((ナルト：よくやったな　木ノ葉丸。
お前だって里の英雄だ。
Good job, Konohamaru!
You're a hero in our village too!
(ヘヘヘヘ…))
俺の…　俺の悪口はいいけど→
I don't care
what you say about me.
ナルト兄ちゃんの悪口は
許さないんだなコレ！
But I won't let you say anything
bad about Big Brother Naruto!
なに！？
What?!
《いったい　あれは？》
What is that?
螺旋丸！
忍法　カマイタチの…。
– Rasengan!
– Ninja Art! Wind Scythe—
影首縛りの術！
Shadow Strangle Jutsu!
うわぁ～！
あ…。
What?
何なんだ　これは？
What is this?
The jutsu passed on
by Naruto himself...
ナルト直伝の術　螺旋丸だ。
The Rasengan.
この小僧が　これほどの術を
ものにしているのか。
That brat mastered
a jutsu this powerful?
（ウドン）木ノ葉丸君！
Konohamaru...
（モエギ）木ノ葉丸ちゃん　大丈夫！？
Are you all right, Konohamaru?
うっ…。
クソッ　何するんだ　コレ！
Damn it!
What are you doing?!
螺旋丸が決まってたら
俺の勝ちだったのに！
If you had let me finish
completing the Rasengan,
I'd have won!
何するんだコレ…。
What was that for?!
だって…　だって…
手柄だとか　俺の勝ちだとか→
Because...
Because you keep talking about
distinguishing yourself
and winning, Konohamaru.
木ノ葉丸ちゃん　戦争になること
喜んでるみたいなんだもん。
It's like you're happy
that war is coming!
そんな…。
That's not...
木ノ葉丸ちゃん。
Konohamaru!
Remember that day!
あの日のこと思い出して！
え？
あの日　木ノ葉丸ちゃんと別れて
Ｃ地区に向かったわ。
That day, I got separated from you,
so I headed towards District C.
そしたら…。
Then...
((ソウ太：うわ～ん
母ちゃん　助けて！
Mommy, help me!
《あの子　危ない。
誰か助けを呼ばないと》
He's in danger.
I have to get help.
《私しかいないんだ。
I'm the only one around.
助けなきゃ…　助けなきゃ…》
I have to help him.
I have to help him!
（ソウ太）うわ～！
♪～
ソウ太！
Sota!
母ちゃん！
Mommy!
Sota!
(ソウ太！))
戦争に出ることだけが→
Fighting in a war isn't
the only way to help the village.
里のために
働くことじゃないと思う。
戦争が始まったら→
When war breaks out,
all the jonin and chunin
won't be in the village.
上忍や中忍たちは
里から出払っちゃうでしょ？
もし　そんな時　敵が攻めてきたら
いったいどうするの！？
What if the enemy attacks us?
Then what?
（ウドン）そうだよ。
That's right.
We have to take the place
of those who are on the battlefield
僕たちが戦地に向かう人たちの
代わりに　この里を→
and protect the elderly and
the children in the village.
お年寄りや子供たちを守らなきゃ
いけないんじゃないの？
((お前が守るべき玉ってのは
何だ？))
Define the King that
you feel you must protect?
♪～
俺　きっと…　きっと守るんだなコレ。
I swear I'm gonna protect them.
じいちゃんや　ばあちゃんを→
All the grandmas and the grandpas,
and the children.
そして　子供たちを…。
里を守るのも重要な任務だからな。
Protecting the village is
a huge responsibility too.
しっかし　運がよかったぜ。
あのまま戦ってたら→
But boy, were you lucky.
If you had kept fighting,
you'd have fallen to
Temari's Wind Scythe Jutsu.
テマリのカマイタチの術で
やられてただろうしな。
クノイチでいちばん
大胆にして残忍な忍に…。
Among all the kunoichi,
she's known as the cruelest one.
ひっ！
フン…　しかし　まぁ
私に本気を出させるなんて→
Still, you're something else,
pushing me to that limit.
やるじゃないか。
オ…　オレ…　オレ…。
I-I... I...
我愛羅には知らせておくよ。
I will report to Gaara
that fine young ones are coming up
among the Hidden Leaf.
木ノ葉には
いい若いのが育ってきてるってね。
まぁ　何年か経ったら
いい忍になってるだろうな。
In a few years, I'm sure
you'll be a good shinobi.
木ノ葉丸ちゃん。
これからどうするの？
Konohamaru...
What'll we do from now?
What else?
決まってんだろ…。
This village is Grandpa's,
the Third Hokage's, treasure.
この里は　じじいの…
三代目　火影の宝だから→
So I'm gonna protect it!
俺は　それを守る。
俺は木ノ葉隠れを守った
三代目　火影の孫だから…。
Because I'm the grandson
of the Third Hokage,
who protected the Village Hidden
in the Leaves!
それに　ナルト兄ちゃんとも
火影の名をかけて→
And because Big Brother Naruto
promised me
that one day, we'd fight
for the title of the Hokage!
いつか勝負するって約束したんだ。
もっともっと修業して→
I'm gonna train more until
I can pulverize Big Brother Naruto!
ナルト兄ちゃんをぶっ倒せるぐらいに
なんなきゃな！
Because becoming
the Hokage is my dream!
火影になるのは
俺の夢だからな！
うん…　そう言ったのか
木ノ葉丸が…。
Is that what Konohamaru said?
確かに　そう言ったっす。
I'm certain of it.
I see. So Konohamaru
said that, huh.
そうか　木ノ葉丸が…。
Not just this necklace!
((この首飾りだけじゃねえよ。
This village is Grandfather's treasure.
この里は　じいちゃんの宝物だ。
So I'm going to protect it.
俺は　それを守るんだ！
Because I'm the grandson
of the First Hokage,
俺は　木ノ葉隠れを作った
初代　火影の孫だからよ。
who founded the Village Hidden
in the Leaves!
フフフ…　言うね。　男に二言はないよ。
Such big talk.
Remember, men don't go
back on their word!
うん！　俺も
じいちゃんみたいに強くなって→
I know!
I'm gonna become like Grandfather
and take on the title
of Hokage one day.
いつか　火影の名前をもらうんだ。
(火影は俺の…。
夢だから！))
– 'Cause becoming the Hokage is my dream.
あいつも元気にやっているかな。
I wonder how he's doing.
fight!!
furishiboru dake sa saigo no itteki mo
I'm going to squeeze it down to the last drop
muda ni dekinaikara now is the time to go
Because I can't waste any of it, Now is the time to go
ikudo tsuma tsukimi to egaita yume wa
The dream that I created many times with you
ima koe kuma atte munune o sasu
I can now put it to words and it pierces my heart
it's not crazy
fight and fight, try and try for you
forever
kimi wa hitori janai
You are not alone
namida koete
Get over the tears
kimi to susunde ikou
I'll keep moving forward with you
nani mo kowaku narute na ii na
I'm not afraid of anything
this is the place to try
soshite bokura kitto tsunaida te o
I'm sure we'll never let go
kesshite hanasanaide asu e kakeru
Of each other's hands as we head for tomorrow
let's sing loudly
we are the one for the future
Next Episode
Getting a marriage proposal so quickly like that.
（美空ひばり）皆様
お変わりございませんか？
Naruto, you're really popular!
It's nothing like that!
美空ひばりです。
Just because Pervy Sage made some careless promise,
I'm paying for it now!
では　最後まで
ごゆっくりお楽しみください。
Well, we are heading to a secret a mission,
so getting involved in any foolish disturbances will be problematic.
We should avoid any unnecessary trouble.
We should rest early and leave first thing in the morning.
Next time: "The Kunoichi of Nadeshiko Village"
The Kunoichi of Nadeshiko Village
Don't! Stop chasing me!